## Erik Hirsch

Apple Valley, CA 92308

Phone: 760 420-4308 | Email: ehirsch760@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/e-hirsch | GitHub: github.com/eh4git

Portfolio: erik-hirsch.com

## Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with previous management experience and a passion for problem solving and collaboration. Effectively communicates with others to streamline the development cycle to produce polished applications. Known by peers for having a strong work ethic and being determined to produce the highest quality results possible.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Technologies: Node, React, React Native, Redux, MySQL, Seguelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Express, jQuery, BootStrap, Semantic, Materialize, Handlebars.js, Ajax, Sass, AWS

## **Projects**

## Along With Me - January 2021

Coming soon to the Google Play Store

Digital book companion enhances readers' experience through audio that accompanies the text.

- Mobile application built with React Native
- Users are authenticated using Firebase Authentication
- Global state is managed by Redux
- User information and personal settings are stored in Firebase

**Key Role(s):** This project has open roles allowing for work on all areas of the application.

Technologies: React Native, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase

## Once Upon An Adventure - July 2020

www.onceuaa.com | github.com/eh4git/once-upon-an-adventure

A collection of educational mini games within an RPG style browser game.

- JavaScript and canvas html elements utilized in the creation of educational mini games.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Implemented React for the front end UI incorporating hooks and Redux to manage state.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles Ajax requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

**Key Role(s):** Animation of sprites, music, and sound effects

**Technologies:** JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Howler, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Redux

## Story Time - June 2020

github.com/eh4git/StoryTime | fathomless-waters-70908.herokuapp.com Personalized children's story generator.

- Responsive Bootstrap UI allows users to easily navigate while using the application.
- Developed front end logic using ¡Query.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): HTML, JavaScript, Front end logic

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, Node

## **Experience**

# Freelance Developer Third Project Development

2020 - Present

CA

Develop full stack web and mobile applications to client's request.

Consult with client's to determine the best course of action for their application.

**Enumerator** 2020 - 2020

## **US Department of Commerce - Bureau Of Census**

Victorville, CA

- Strong communication skills used to engage and connect with the public.
- Work 100% independently to complete daily tasks.

Delivery Driver United Parcel Service 2019 - 2020

Victorville, CA

- Recognized for strong work ethic.
- Awarded by management for achieving highest performance on multiple occasions.

## Project Manager

2015 - 2019

## **Rick Kittson Hardwood Flooring**

Irvine, CA

- Supervised a small team to maintain quality and to complete projects in a timely manner.
- Recognized for strong work ethic.

## **Cooling Operator**

2017 - 2018

Golden Island

Rancho Cucamonga, CA

- Reduced labor costs by 50% through assisting in the implementation of new cooling systems and procedures.
- Attained recognition for excellent attendance record.

#### Education

## UCLA Extension - Los Angeles, CA

## Full Stack Web Development - Certificate

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

## Victor Valley College - Victorville, CA

## **Management Certificate of Completion - Certificate**

31 Unit program that teaches the skills that are required for management. Courses included Accounting, Economics, Computer Literacy, Human Resource Management, Legal Environment of Business, Business Math, and Business Communications.

#### **Additional Courses**

## Scrimba

The React Boot Camp - August 2020, Tricky Parts of JavaScript - September 2020, Learn Regular Expressions - September 2020

#### **Amazon Web Services**

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials, Introduction to AWS Storage Gateway, Introduction to Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3), Amazon Simple Storage Service - Closer look - Part 1&2, AWS Storage Offerings